Hello everyone, welcome to my channel.
Today we are going to talk about how to build a real scene and render it in colo.
How to build a real scene and render it in colo.
built a real scene and render it in colo.
Let's go ahead and start Today's live streaming.
Today I will bring you a video of how to build a real scene and render it in Colo.
here we are.
Here are some previews that we gave you before.
We can take a look at the whole scene and the rendering.
It's all built and rendered in cloud.
We're going to use a lot of material during this time.
And these materials will also be in our live broadcast.
After the end, I'll share it with you on WeChat.
Remember to go to the WeChat public number and reply to the live material to get it.
Okay, first of all, we can take a look at the scene effect of the live broadcast tonight.
We can see that we will use a dress skirt and a virtual model here.
These are all in the latest version of our cloud.
There will be in the commercial city of Connec.
I will guide you to download and import.
First of all, we need to be in the cloud.
Before the live broadcast, let me introduce you to some of the materials we will use today.
Here I will share with you a folder like this.
There will be a scene 1 and scene 2 in it.
Each scene 1 and scene 2 will be covered by four folders.
We can see these four folders.
We can open and check.
In the first folder, it will be covered by some of these scene model folders.
In the second folder, it will be covered by some of these scene model folders.
In the third folder, it will be covered by some of these scene model folders.
The third one is our jdr environment sticker.
The fourth is some continuous pattern of the four sides.
It is convenient for us to do some scene ground and use.
These folders will also be shared to you.
Okay, first of all, before we make a scene.
Before that, you can load a virtual model, and the main purpose is that we need a virtual model to do a reference, and here we use Claude's new model, Yuna.
Next, let's make a larger board.
This large board can be drawn very large, and it can cover about one-fourth of our screen.
After drawing, the board will be a little bit short, but it doesn't matter.
We can choose this board and reduce its particle diameter.
We can see that the board has been drawn. It is a very large board.
This board can be used as the ground for our entire scene.
Next, we can choose our board and change its particle diameter to 700.
Why is that?
Because our 700 is the largest particle diameter.
Remember that the ground board must be changed to a large particle diameter.
Because it doesn't need to be included in our calculation.
We can rotate the whole board, and then right-click it in the 3D window and choose to move to the center of the ground.
In this way, we can see that the whole board is used as a ground for our scene.
Next, let's take a look at some of the materials in the folder that will be used next.
This is what I just showed you.
We have such a four-sided continuous file folder.
There will be some real leaves in the folder.
Let's paste this file first on this default material.
Then we can zoom in and see.
After zooming in, we can use the edit tool to make the whole picture larger.
Let's make it a little bit smaller.
For the live broadcast effect, let's delete the model's skin first.
In this way, we have created such a ground effect.
It's actually very simple.
Just draw a very large board.
Next, we can start to import some models for our scene.
Because our whole operation is done in the 3D window.
For example, we only need to display the 3D window.
Let's switch it.
Next, let's open this folder.
In the folder, there is a 3D title file.
Let's open it.
There will be a lot of such files in it.
There will be such a model in each file.
For example, let's open the first one.
We can see through the solid picture that it is such a tree-like model.
How do we import it?
In this folder, there is a file called .fbx.
We drag this file directly to our 3D window.
After dragging it in, we click on it.
Then select the type of loading as increase.
Then change its object type to copy.
This is a very important step.
We click OK.
The model that is imported can be seen in the center of our map.
It will be displayed.
We can see that this is a model like this.
If you look at it like this, the model is ugly.
Next, let's see how to make it look better.
We are still in the folder just now.
You can see my live broadcast here.
After we open this folder,
you will find that there are several such stickers in addition to this model.
The colored one is a texture picture.
The purple one is a hair line picture.
We can select the model.
In our case, we drag its texture picture directly to its object.
This is the texture of the attribute processor.
Then you can see that this texture is pasted in.
Then we select the hair line and paste the hair line picture in.
OK.
You can see that after this model is imported,
we add a sticker to it.
It will make the whole model particularly real.
Next, we can see that this model is slightly darker than the surrounding environment.
Because there are some FBX,
it may bring some gray after it is imported.
For example, it may be gray or black.
Then we can adjust the color of the model.
Then we can see that after the model is imported,
it can freely adjust its size in our 3D window.
How to adjust it?
We can see that after selecting the model,
there is a ratio in the attribute processor on the right.
On the ratio side, we can see that it has x and y.
There will be a fixed ratio below.
We only need to enter any size.
The three ratios will do the same.
Then we change its ratio to a size of 3500.
When we use our moving model,
we must use the world coordinate axis.
We can make a parallel to the model and a horizontal parallel to the top and bottom.
You can see that in this way,
we will place the model slightly above our board.
Let it have such a contact surface.
You can see that in this way,
it merges our model and our scene together.
At the same time, we can adjust the ratio on the right
to adjust the size of the model.
In addition to the attribute processor,
we can also select the model.
There is such a mark on the upper right corner of its locator.
After we click on this mark,
our model will look like this.
We can drag the three axes,
x, y and z,
to adjust the length and height ratio of the model.
In this way,
we can adjust the effect of the model at the 3D window.
Let's move its position again.
Let's rotate it and place it behind our model.
For example,
I have already inserted a model into G-Gang.
Can I copy it out?
It's actually very simple.
We just right-click on the model and select copy and paste.
This is why we just talked about
that when we insert,
we must select copy and paste
because the copy and paste can be copied and pasted directly.
This is very convenient for our building scene.
Let's use the positioning ball tool
to adjust its position
and make it connect to our ground.
When you move the model,
please press 2468 on our keyboard.
In this way,
we can move it in the right angle.
If the model is like this,
it will be easier to move it.
Let's adjust it.
We can use the same model
to rotate its angle
and adjust its size
to achieve a rhythm change in the whole scene.
OK.
Here,
I move the ground of our board a little bit down
because it may lead to
an uneven ground later.
Then let it go down a little bit.
OK.
Next,
let's open the folder
to see the second material package.
We also click the insert button
and select increase.
Then select the object type as copy.
Here,
you can pay attention to
the ratio I use here
is a centimeter.
Why?
Because of these models,
if your ratio here
uses millimeters,
the input will be very small.
It may only have
50 mm or 30 mm,
which is very small.
Then we can change its ratio
to centimeters first.
In this way,
the input will be a little bigger.
We click OK.
After the input is entered,
we can see that it is still
in the center of our world coordinate axis.
We also open it
in this folder.
After opening it,
we add its texture
and our發現 picture
to it.
Then let's adjust this.
This is the color of the model.
OK.
Here,
we can see that
our model is a little white
and the dark color of our ground
is a little different.
We can take the initiative
to add a color to this model
so that it has a positive and negative effect
and can be matched with our scene.
You can see that
I choose a different color here.
It will be stacked together
and more integrated with our scene.
OK.
Next,
I want to make this model
as a ground.
Our ground must not be so flat,
right?
It needs some high and low changes.
We can choose this model
and adjust its ratio to the maximum.
We give it a 5000 first
and then adjust it to the size of 8000.
You can see that
the whole model
will have a larger effect
on this side.
Of course,
we can see that
it has a high starting point.
We can choose our 3D
texture
and we can see that
it has a high starting point.
We can see that
it has a high starting point
and we can see that
the 3D adjustment axis
can adjust the whole plane
to a height
so that it doesn't have to be too rough
or too obvious.
Let's make it a little flat.
OK.
Next,
we can over- duplicate this shape
and put it on our board.
In this way,
we can make our whole scene
change from all angles
from all angles
At the same time,
we can adjust the whole picture
by 3D adjusting axis
to make the whole terrain higher and lower
to make it more changeable
Ok, turn it around
Then we copy this to the opposite position
Ok, we can simply adjust its position
to make it more natural to our scene
So when we build the scene
I just told you that
we have a curve line
in addition to the texture
Why do we need to import this curve line?
Because we can see that
if you delete the texture
due to the curve line
our terrain will be more obvious
Let's go on a
Double click another image
to copy it and place it
in the front and right covered spots of the model
OK, let's take a look at the whole scene, OK, we can see that I show you the grid on this side.
In fact, these models that I share with you are relatively low on the grid.
So we can add a lot of models and it won't take up a lot of grid space.
So you can see that these grid spaces are very small.
OK, let's import another model.
There is a tree-like model here.
Let's import this model directly.
If you don't know what model is in this folder,
there will be a sorting chart in each folder.
You can look at this sorting chart first.
You will know what this model is.
Then we still choose to add as a copy and then click OK.
OK, after we import it, we also paste the texture of our model and its hair line.
OK, increase its hair line value.
Since it is a tree, we can adjust its proportion a little bit.
Let's take a look at the whole scene.
Let's put the whole tree behind it.
The whole tree will also have some roots like this.
The range is below.
Then we can adjust its position.
Here, I still feel that I need to adjust its left and right.
When we are operating, we can press 246 more times to see its different angles.
Let's see if the position of the model placed in this angle is appropriate.
Or whether it matches our whole scene.
OK, and then here, we can see that there is a tree like this on this side.
Then we import the tree like this into it.
OK, after we import it, we can see that it is also in the center of the model.
First of all, let's adjust its texture.
Let me adjust the size first.
Then we find these texture pictures and paste them in.
OK, and then we move this model to its...
First of all, add a color to it.
Because it's a little pale.
It's a little bit out of our environment.
Click OK.
Then we rotate this model.
Where to put it?
Put it in the back of its side.
In this case, I want to make a tree next to it.
So that the tree falls down like this.
And there are some effects of rotting in the ground.
We can move it and put it back as much as possible.
You can see that in this way.
The whole scene will be more natural when it is integrated.
We can adjust the size.
Make it a little bit bigger.
That tree is a little bit thin.
Let's make it a little bit thicker.
OK.
OK, let's adjust the position of its one.
OK, let's adjust the position of his one.
Then, we can take this model.
mechanic side nossos
Let's take a look at the file folder.
What other materials are there?
You can see that in the photos of previous episodes.
Let's go back and look at the last episodes.
Let's go back to last episodes.
Let's see.
There are some standing decorations on this side
Then we will import it again
When you are operating here
Be sure not to slide your hand
Don't click on open
If you open it, your current file will be covered
Be sure to choose to add
If you are worried about it
You can save your project files at any time
Don't keep operating without saving
After this model is imported
We still give it a sticker
Stick it in
First stick it on its texture
Then stick this sticker on the hair line
Ok, let's adjust the size of the whole costume
I will adjust it to 5000 first
What about the back
I want to do this
It feels like a forest behind it
So I will put a few more trees in the back
Make it big and small
There is such a change in the scene
This tree seems a bit thick
Let's adjust it
Make it a little thinner
I'll stretch it out first
Then adjust its proportion up and down through our axis
Put it back
It seems a bit big
We can copy this tree directly with Ctrl-C and Ctrl-V
Put it in the back right
Put it in this position
Ok, then I will put it in the back right
You can also copy a few more
And then put it on
Because we'll be rendering it later
Not only in one angle
There might be more angles to render
Then I can copy a few more out
Then this is what I was just emphasizing
When we import, we should import it as a duplicate
Because in this way
It will be more convenient if we copy and paste
Ok, in this way
There is a general form in our picture
It's a ground
It's this grassy forest feeling
There will be some corrupt trees behind
There are also fallen trees and trees that grow bigger and so on
Let's take a look at some of the documents
Is there a slightly smaller number
You can import it in and use it
Here, there is a tree like this
Let's import this tree first
When you import it
Is to select this FBX file
Don't choose the wrong one
Or we paste the picture on it
After you paste it, you can adjust its width and height with the mouse
Let's make it a little bigger first
And then put it back
We can see that this tree is a little too thick
It's clinging to the back
Let's use this axis to adjust it a little bit
Pull it back
Then copy it out
And then I'm going to put a few more of them
In this way
What about our trees
He has this kind of a little bit thicker
A little bit thinner
That is, there are big trees and small trees
It will form a comparison like this
If we are all the same size
The rhythm of the whole picture will not be very good
We can go through the size of the tree to adjust the effect of the picture
Then let's take a look at what kind of material there is in other documents
Here, there is a tree like this
It's relatively large
Then you can put it in first
See where to use it
And then?
Let's adjust its size first
Let's make it a little smaller
See if it looks good
There should be strong enough
Then let's change it to thicker
But it's not
You'll be able to invest it
Then
And then we lower the volume
Then we lower the volume
Then look at the versus
See r戎
Have a wide view
It's full of us
See r戎
Get in a wave
the effect will be better
not rich in the right angle
and when it reaches the side
or the other side
there will be no effect
then we copy the previous tree
and move its position
move into the ground
here we can see
the fallen trees
let's see
if we can use it
this kind of
If we want to see the effect of the line and the tree growing together, then we can put it back a little, put it to the side, put it together with the tree leading it, so that our picture will be richer.
Okay, I'm going to pull this model a little bit higher, a little bit higher, so that it's a little bit higher than the object next to it.
Our building scene is a process of slowly adjusting. You have to go slowly to think about its details.
Okay, and then we're going to do it again.
Let's take a look at the new scene, the new model.
Okay, let's take a look at this side.
Well, these are all trees.
There's a tree here.
And then there's some rock here.
Let's look for a rock.
Okay, this side, there's a piece of this.
The rock that grows green.
I'm going to pour it in.
Oh, when I just poured it in, this type was chosen wrong.
I chose a virtual model.
I'm going to delete this stone and pour it back in.
Because our virtual model, it's a lot of trouble to copy it.
So we're going to import it as a copy.
Okay, and then we're going to change the color of this model.
And then we're going to paste our picture in there.
Okay, we can see that there's a rock here.
It's a little bit of a match with our scene.
We can just put it in our whole scene.
It's a little bit richer than our scene.
Okay, let's go back to our scene.
Okay, we're going to look down.
Is there any other material?
And then there's a bridge here that looks like this.
And then this bridge.
We can put it in this forest.
We'll take it as a bridge that's a long time away.
And then the trees all grow out of the gaps in this bridge.
Let's put it back.
Let's take a look.
Let's adjust its size.
Then we put the model of the sticker to it to load into
After loading, we can see that the color of the bridge will be a little bit lighter
Our scene feels more like a forest
We can choose this bridge and add a little bit of color to it
Yellow so that it can be melted together with the picture
Click to choose different colors to take a look
If you can see this color, it is more compatible with our picture
Let's adjust it to this color
Then let's see if there are any other materials
OK
There are some stone lamps here
It's more compatible with our bridge
We can also import the stone lamp
Then put the sticker and its hair line on it
This lamp is a little big
Let's put it back and take a look
Let's adjust the proportion of the stone lamp
Let's make it a little bit smaller
You can see that when we build the scene
It's this kind of big and small
This is to create the bigger part of our whole picture
After setting the overall style
Go find some small elements
Go inside to insert
A picture that enriches the whole scene
OK
In this way
We put some of these models into it
Let's save it
We can zoom in and see the effect
OK
Next, we can build the main tree
The grass and the stone
We can insert some of these plants
Let's look at the second folder
There will be some of these plants
There will be some plastic pictures here
We open the folder directly
It will have many small folders
In these paper folders
Each paper folder will have one of these FBX files
We put this file into it
I choose to add it as a copy
Click to confirm
The second one in our file folder
It's mainly some plant materials
Let's take a look at these plants
This is what it looks like after being inserted
Wait a minute
OK
This is a leaf
Let's change another one
Change another material
Let's reinitialize one
Change a V1
Take a look
Sometimes when you are inserting a file
Just met your system
In auto-preservation
It will
Lock in that place
This is very normal
Then we introduce it
After that, we can see
What is this
After we import it, we can see that it is such a grass, we can adjust the position of the grass, first of all, the color of this model is a little gray, we adjust it to white, and then we find the sticker and paste the sticker of this model into it.
Then the sticker in the 3D plant folder will not be on the surface, we need to find the texture folder in this folder, and then there will be our stickers in it.
The whole folder contains this one sticker, so we only need to open this one.
Of course, you can only use this plant to copy, because we can adjust its size.
First, pull this plant a little higher, and then adjust it a little higher, use this positioning tool, and then move it to its side.
The grass will definitely grow on such stones or tree trunks, then we can put it in these places.
Then we can put it in these places.
Just use Ctrl C and Ctrl V to copy and paste it.
It's very simple.
Then, if we want to make some comparisons, you can make some grass a little bigger and some grass a little smaller.
We can do the big one first, and then copy all the big ones.
Then adjust the proportion.
I make this one a little bigger, and then copy another one, and then adjust the position of this little grass.
Then make this little grass a little smaller.
Then adjust the size of this little grass, create such a comparison.
We can see that we are now basically adding some small plants, so that our picture is richer.
We move it back a little bit.
Because it's farther back, we can adjust it by adjusting its ratio.
Even if you see it at the front, But it doesn't emphasize the main effect of our front here.
We can see how far away it is.
Put it this way.
We can add some between the stone gap in the distance and between the canopies.
You can see that I made a very small one here.
I put it next to him.
Let him have a picture of not only the big one but also some small ones.
Okay, next time we're going to pour another plant.
We can find a flower like this.
Some of these flowers in this folder.
And then I'm going to give him this model and I'm going to find him a V1 and I'm going to pour it in.
Okay, click OK.
After you've done that, you'll also find that this flower is gray.
Because he brought his own color.
Let's change the color to white first.
And then we're going to paste our picture in there.
It's the same thing in this folder.
The text of this folder.
And then I'm going to paste it on our texture picture.
This one, then, is on the hair line picture.
Okay, where do we put this flower?
Put it between the grass.
He's not going to grow one under the model's foot, is he?
We can copy it and paste it directly.
Use the locator to adjust its position and rotate it.
Like this one in the back.
We can make it a little bigger.
This way, he can be seen in the back, but it doesn't have to emphasize the main body in front of it.
This flower is a little high, so you can put it back.
Just don't put it in the front.
The front is too eye-catching.
Then we choose another flower in the same file wall and then we import it.
The size of this model, the larger the file, the bigger the model, the smaller the model.
So we can change its color first.
And then stick this copy in there.
And then paste it in there.
Okay?
This is a multi-headed flower, let's put it back
You can see that I put this flower to the back
Because if you do this, even if we show it from other angles, it will show this flower without experience
In this way, it will not be too empty at the back
Because we only show this flower from the back
The plants are in front, let's put it back
We have to press 2 or 5 to zoom in and see the effect of the whole picture
Don't just look at one place
Let's put it in one place
Next, let's put these flowers in a random way
Let it grow randomly, such as in front, left, and side
Doesn't burst
Don't put it in the wrong place
Let it grow randomly, such as in front, left, and side
Does not transform the combination
It doesn't answer to the previous water
OK, this is a pretty good place
OK let's save it
That's good
To optimize this scene, let's adjust the position and number of this grass
OK, then I have downloaded a file of a mushroom like this before, let's find out where the mushroom is
Let's see where it is
Yes, we can see that it is a group of small mushrooms like this, we drag the FBX of this mushroom directly into it
Then add it as a copy, click confirm
Then we can see that there are a lot of mushrooms, because it is a collection file, it has a lot of small mushrooms in it
Let's move this mushroom out one by one
OK
Today's material will be shared in the background of our public account, then you can go to the public account background, leave a message, live material, and you can get today's material file
If you don't pay attention to our public account, you can pay attention to the bottom left corner
Then we choose these mushrooms, first paste this sticker in
This is a typical Yunnan mushroom, it is red umbrella, white pole, very representative
Then let's adjust the size of these mushrooms first, then let's choose a few mushrooms to make them bigger
Let's move it to the back, because the mushroom is a group, it will definitely grow around the tree
Then put these mushrooms next to the rotten tree
The little mushroom is very cute
Afterward, adjust the size of mushrooms
This mushroom will just lie down
It is OK it will just be graded c and v
You can see it if you haven't looked for them yet
You don't have to look for them yet, just write and move them with your Braille
Because sometimes it will be graded below the ground
or be covered by other models
So you have to move it to have a look
Where is it usually covered by models
Because we have more models now
Ok, this mushroom is a little bit white
Let's make the color of this mushroom a little bit darker
It's the same as choosing a model
Just add color to it
This is very simple
Ok, let me see what else needs to be adjusted
Let's change the color of this mushroom
And then we choose this mushroom
See if we can copy it
An output
Let's adjust the angle
Copy one of them in this direction
Ok, so what about this
We can rotate and look at the whole
The whole environment
Is this environment ok around the model
So what happens next
You'll find that the whole scene of this model
It's a little bit empty on the left side of the model
Let's copy this model a little bit
In this way
We can look at it from other angles
For example, on the right side
On the right side
On the left side
It can make his picture not so empty as it should be
And then let's copy these little mushrooms
and the one will come out
Ok, this mushroom
It must be arranged around this tree
Don't put it back in place
on the stone bridge
when you create your own
to do some reasonable things
OK, let me save the project file
well, in this case
we put the whole scene
built almost
from the very beginning
we put some big tree, stone bridge
tree, tree, soil, stone, and so on
and then we put some small
for example, grass, flowers, mushrooms
to create the whole scene
then we can
in the software
directly in our library
you can see there are three buttons
right
our third button
is our Connect button
Connect is our business city
you can use your Closet account
to do business here
you can log in
whatever you upload on Connect
will be displayed here
then you can choose
my backpack folder
inside
there will be some files
that I saw in Connect or locally
you can download directly
here
we can see
all the ones that say Freight
can be downloaded directly to the local
it's convenient for us to use
here
because I'm just building a scene
so I don't make clothes
I just go to Connect
to download one
such a dress group
OK, let's see
OK, this is the one that we have downloaded before
I just click on it to add
it can be added to my scene
click OK
then I need to change the model
to it
because this is a white mother
our new model
is also on Connect
you can also download and use
in addition to the model and clothing
we have also updated
such as shoes
zipper movements and so on
a lot of materials will be in it
you can download and use
it
let me show you
what you need
I need to do next
to the clothing model
the action of
a change
I will first put the ground of the side of the
selection
for him to return fire
you ask him
you do not need to participate in the calculation
we click a few of the resources in this
Freight
you can Lord
Freight options
there is free
you can see in the library here
here is also a free one for free
Click on it and it will show you that it is free
It doesn't mean that everything is free if you click on it
I will turn this version back on
Then select the costume
I will lower its particle diameter a little bit
Increase it a little bit
Then I will simulate it will be slower
I will change it to a shoe like this
You can see that it is a tie shoe like this
I will change it to such a posture
I will change the color of the shoes first
It seems to be white
Change it to such a rose gold
Click OK
Then we are still on my connect
Find such a women's costume
Then you can see that I have some mouse
Put it on it will show download
It means you can download
Click double click
Let's see if there is anything below
Or this action
Double click on open to confirm
OK
Then let's take a look
I adjusted the costume
After that, I will raise its particle diameter
Raise its costume a little bit
It's too low
Adjust the particle diameter of the costume
Adjust it to 5
Then we will open the simulation again
OK
Then we remove the hardening of the costume
In this case
We will put the model's clothes
Put the model's clothes and shoes into it
And give it an action
In this case
We can enter our one
Blending window
To check the overall effect
Let's hide it first
We click
Click
Let's set the size of a picture first
I use a 1 9 20 times 10 80 first
A horizontal deck
Click synchronization
Click agree
As soon as the mixing bottle hits the button
Okay
Then you have a process
OK, you can see that this scene has been rendered.
Next, let's talk about the second point, which is about the rendering and lighting techniques of our real scene.
First of all, we choose lighting settings.
There is a skylight on the side of lighting settings.
The first one below the skylight is the environment image.
We click on the plus sign on the environment image side.
Then we can load some of these photographic lighting.
It is an HDR image.
Here I have prepared some effects of HDR for you.
Let's take a look.
In our material file, there is a folder called HDR.
We double-click to open it.
There are three scenery stickers in it.
We can take a look.
OK, let's copy the path of this HDR folder.
After copying, we open the file and input it here.
Then we can directly choose an HDR image.
Let's open this HDR image.
What is the difference between this HDR image and the normal image?
It will cover some environmental information, including light and so on.
It can be rendered in your 3D window, in your rendering window.
OK, then we can see that this background is black and there is no scene.
That's because we need to open the display of the skylight here.
After opening the display of the skylight, it will appear.
Let's click the synchronization rendering.
This scene is a bit dark.
Let's change it.
Let's copy the path first.
After copying, let's take a look at the original file.
Let's choose a 65 light effect.
You can see that this picture will be brighter.
Then we can adjust the intensity of the light to adjust the entire ambient light.
Then it will be a little brighter.
You can see that in this way, we can integrate an HDR effect.
Even if we didn't make a lot of trees in the back,
it will also show a more dense forest effect in the back.
OK, let's take a look at it from a distance.
You can see that the ground is a little bright.
It's because our previous texture color is a little bit lighter.
Let's activate this plate first.
Let's adjust the color of this material first.
Let's stop the rendering first.
Let's activate this ground first.
After activating it, let's look directly at the 3D window and adjust it a little faster.
Let's choose the material directly.
Add a color to it.
Click Done.
OK, Now, the entire ground and the wouldn't be this tree and the ground are close to the surface.
Good.
Next we can adjust the whole photographic literary lens angle.
Because our HDR picture, it's a 360 degree full view picture like this,
you can smart it up to the worship lens angle to make it work like this.
to make it rotate like this
to see the effect under each lighting
and environment
We can see here that we need to add some light
I want to make the model's clothes more prominent
so I click on the square light
I choose the front of the model
and add a square light in front of it
I first rotate the light board
and put the light board in front of the model
In this way, we can give the model's clothes
a separate light
to make it more prominent during rendering
We change the width and height of the light to 2000
which is 2 meters
This is OK for us
It can block the whole clothes
We can increase the intensity of the light board
and turn off the display
In this way, let's click on the synchronization rendering again
to see the effect
OK. We can see that in this way
the model's position will be brighter
Let's see what kind of lights we can adjust
The lighting adjustment is a long process, we need to adjust it a little bit, and adjust it while rendering to achieve a more perfect state.
Let's adjust the lighting angle.
If you feel that the light in your environment does not have a main light, and you want it to have a main light effect, then we can add a square light.
The square light is a light that can hit a relatively large number in your 3D environment, which is a bit like the effect of sunlight.
Then we can choose a direction to hit the light.
For example, you can see it in the upper right corner of the model.
After adding a square light,
the effect of contrast between light and dark will be more obvious.
It will have a main light from its upper right to hit it.
So the square light on this side is a relatively large lighting effect.
Then we increase the intensity of the lighting a little bit.
Let's take a look again.
You can also give it some colors.
For example, I want it to have a light yellow warm light effect like the dim light in the early morning.
Then you can give it a light yellow color.
Let it have a light color.
Then you can see that even if we rotate the screen in the 3D window,
because the scene is three-dimensional, so we rotate to every angle,
it is a more real effect.
So you can adjust the light on this side.
Let's get a bluish light edge for this example.
The suitability of clay tasty and disturb the light on the screen,
but if we give a幾分魔物色,
I want to get a strong light look at this light.
Let's talk about a new point of knowledge
When we render the scene, if we want the whole picture to be more transparent
Then we can select the lens attribute in the background of the 3D window
Then we choose the default lens
Then at the end of the lens, it will play a view here in our monitor
The view is a default 15 camera lens
Then we can change it to 35, then change it to 40
You will find that when you change it to 40, your picture will be far away
When you zoom in, your 3D window will have a more obvious sense of transparency
This is of course based on your need to match the scene
To decide whether you want to adjust the size of the camera's vision
Let's move the ground up
Next, I want to add some star lights around it
Let's take a look
But the whole environment is relatively bright
Adding this star light is a bit out of place
Let's take a look at the light, for example, like this square light
Let's make it a little lighter
Then the light intensity of the whole skylight is also adjusted to a very low
Let the whole picture press down
Let the light of the ball be a little brighter
Create a sense of overall atmosphere like this
We can add a few more star lights like this
Then the 3D model can also be added
We can see that the 3D model is very beautiful
Let's see the blue color
Now we have the blue color
And the green color
This is the sun light
It's like a fish-eye lens
I'll give him a few more lights
The front and back are about a hundred
Okay, here's the synchronization
We can take a look
This is what I've added so far
The effect of a few lights
Okay, let's pause
I'll add one more to the right
Because of his picture
Add a little light to the left
Such a light bulb
You'll find that the light bulb I added
It's basically on the ground
He has a feeling of being raised from the ground
Like we're in the square
Or some of the decorations we've seen
You can adjust the radius of this ball
Even if it's far away
You can see him
ok
Let's see
How to
can
You can adjust it again
There are two such stone lamps in the back
We can put this stone lamp in the middle
Give him some of these ball lights
Let this stone light up
It's very simple
Let's add a ball
Just move it into the stone lamp
It's a little hard to get
We can take a few more turns to take a look
OK
Once you're in
We can change its color to yellow
I want him to make a little bit of a twist
This kind of candlelight effect
This yellow
Then add another one
O
OK, let's click on the synchronization to see the effect.
OK, let's click on synchronization.
OK, let's click on synchronization to see the effect.
based on our reference picture to build a scene effect of their own
that the second scene
I also want to talk about is that I used such a platform in it
such a lighting effect
that this is actually very simple
you just need to draw a few more square panels
and then the middle of the panel
to set it to light effect
we can do it
we can set this side of this panel
here to set it to a light attribute
you can show some of this
lighting such a scene
this is our second scene
you can practice
you can send the final practice file to our WeChat public number
and then you can reply to us
and then let's see who does it better
ok
this is our live content today
and then you have any questions
you can leave a comment and we will try to answer some of your questions
ok
and then I see a lot of students are asking where our material is downloaded
we can go and have a look at it
we recommend a software called Bridge to everyone
then this software
you can search for it in Bilibili
it has a lot of people sharing some download methods
then here it can directly download some Chinese models like this
you can see here it has a lot of models
you can download it
for example, there are buildings, food
and some historical buildings and so on
then this full name is called Quicks Bridge
if you are interested
you can go and find out
if you don't have time to download it
you can leave a comment in the background of our public number
and then you can get a material file today
to practice and use
ok
do you have any other questions
our live broadcast will end in five minutes
why 7.0 Chinese version will be a little strange
shouldn't the 7.0 Chinese version make it easier for everyone to use it?
yes, I also talked about the swimsuit before
if you are more interested in the special effects
you can also watch some of our special effects live broadcasts before
네,不 어
ok
say hi to everyone wise
Let me remind once again
when we are saving your project document
if you want to save these light sheets we made
you can click the file
then choose another to save
there is an activity called rendering properties
we can directly use these
your rendering settings feel said light ah largeinis ah large blacks add Pokémon lights effect administration in the software program that expressing various properties homme can directly use close from front side may hold cooler arch so that it is not locked at the end of the case you see yeah there are so many changes, but will go outside every day, let me take the next three days
and so on, you can pack it up and save it so that it's convenient for us to use it directly next time.
OK, I see that some of the students are asking how to download the model.
Also in our software, you can directly use Konec in this library, the Konec of this
piece and then choose to pull him.
You can click on the free selection and then you can see our new model yuna here.
And our new model.
This gold number, and then you can see their hair, including the posture, is here.
You can directly download it and use it.
There is also a new model here.
And we will go to the consistence section, and then there is a new model here.
then you can directly download and use it.
There are a lot of this kind of posture preview
There are some glasses
The men's and women's clothes are all there
And then you pull it down
There are some shoes
We recently updated a lot of shoes materials
All kinds of styles
Men's and women's shoes are available
You can go and download it as soon as possible
Where to download
It's in the software
It's your upper left corner
Look at the library
You must use the latest version
Just use our latest version 7.0.358
If you're using the old version
Maybe not in the new version
Isn't there three buttons in this library
You choose the third one
Connect this one
There's an N color N
You click in and you have it
How to download the background
Today we are going to give you an explanation of how to create a 3D background
You can use it all the time after you build it yourself
OK, then our live broadcast is about to end
Do you have any questions
If not, we're going to end
And then look forward to your work!
If you have a good new work
You can upload it to our Kinect mall
You can also share it with our WeChat public number background
OK, well, our live broadcast is coming to an end
And then if you have any questions
You can leave a message in our public number.
Thank you for watching!
We hope you have a great day!
See you in the next video!